Guide to the Gustaf Sobin Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Writings, 1955-2005; Series II; 37; (37 boxes)
  - Towards the Blanched Alphabets (1998)
    - Part 1: "Of Air Augmented," "The Body Being Porous," "Transparent Itineraries:1994," drafts (Box 37)
    - Part 2: "Late Bronze," "Early Iron," drafts and notes, 1998; 4 (Box 37)
    - Part 3: "According to Senaca," "Fugues: there's only 'there'," drafts, 1995 (Box 37)
    - Part 3: "Replique," "Contrapuntal," "Fastia," drafts, 1996 (Box 37)
    - Part 3: "Spiritus Asper," "Toward the Blanched Alphabets," "Chaselas," drafts, 1994 (Box 37)
    - Part 3: "Pseudo Semantic," "Transparent Itineraries: 1995," drafts, 1995-1996 (Box 37)
    - Part 3: "Blue, She said," "Flora," "The Guitarist," drafts, 1995 (Box 37)
    - Part 4: "Reading Sarcophagi," drafts and notes, 1996; 3 (Box 37)
    - Part 5: "A World of Letters," "Nevermore than the Neither," "Crypt," "Aura Aureole," drafts and notes, 1996 (Box 37)
    - Part 5: "Barroco: an Essay," "A Penultimate Grammar," drafts, 1996 (Box 37)
    - Part 5: "Transparent Itineraries: 1996," "Garde Fou," drafts (Box 37)
    - Part 5: "The Meaning of Things," "Odess," "Breath's Successive Vertebrae," drafts, 1996 (Box 37)
    - Part 5: "Palms," "Oyster," "Abduction," "Called St. Space," drafts, 1994-1996 (Box 37)
    - Final typescript, proofsheets, rejected material, 1992-1996; 3 (Box 38)
    - Material for "Transparent Itineraries: 1992-1996" (Box 38)
  - In Pursuit of a Vanishing Star (2002)
    - Plot outlines, character sketches, research material, 1999; 2 (Box 38)
    - Iconographic material, undated (Box 38)
    - Choice of titles, preparation notes, 1999 (Box 38)
    - Chapter 1, first draft, 1999 (Box 38)
    - Chapter 2, first draft, 1999 (Box 38)
    - Chapter 3, first draft, 1999; 2 (Box 38)
    - Chapter 3 & 4, first draft, 1999 (Box 38)
    - Version A, p. 1-26, first finished draft, 1999 (Box 38)
    - Version A, p. 28-57, first finished draft, 1999 (Box 38)
    - Version A, p. 52-94, first finished draft, 1999 (Box 38)
    - Version A, Part 1, first completed draft, undated (Box 39)
    - Version A, Part 2, first completed draft, undated (Box 39)
    - Version A, Part 3, first completed draft, undated (Box 39)
    - Version A, Part 3 Continued, draft, undated; 2 (Box 39)
    - Version A, Part 3 & 4 Concluded, draft, undated (Box 39)
    - Version A, Corrections, typescript, undated (Box 39)
    - Version B, Corrected, typescript, undated; 2 (Box 39)
    - Version C, draft, 1999; 2 (Box 39)
    - Version C, Corrections, draft, 1999; 2 (Box 39)
    - Revisions toward Version D, draft, 2000 (Box 39)
    - Version D, typescript, 2000 (Box 39)
    - Version D, revised typescript, 2000 (Box 39)
    - Rewrite toward Version E, draft, 2000 (Box 40)
    - Version E, draft, 2000; 5 (Box 40)
    - Version E, transcript of drafts, 2000 (Box 40)
    - "In Pursuit of a Vanishing Star," typescript, undated (Box 40)
    - "In Pursuit of a Vanishing Star," corrections, undated; 2 (Box 40)
    - Version F, final draft, undated (Box 40)
    - Corrections by editors, typescript, 2001; 2 (Box 40)
      Includes "foul material" returned to the author by the editors.
  - Ladder of Shadows (2009)
    - Introduction, draft, undated (Box 41)
    - Notes, first complete draft, 2000 (Box 41)
    - "Cryptochristianity: the Sarcophagi of Arles," notes and draft, 2000 November (Box 41)
    - "Terra Sigillata," 2nd draft, 1999 November (Box 41)
    - "Relics," draft, 2001 January (Box 41)
    - "The Blossoming of Numbers (The Baptistry at Riez)," draft, undated (Box 41)
      Includes postcards
    - "The Selection of Shadows: Sarcophagi 2," draft, undated (Box 41)
    - "City of God," draft, 1998 February (Box 41)
    - "Laying the Dragon Low," draft, undated (Box 41)
    - "The Dark Ages: a History of Omissions," draft, undated (Box 41)
    - "The Blue Tears of Sainte-Marthe," essay, undated (Box 41)
    - "The Blind Arcade: Reflections on an Early Medieval Sarcophagus," early draft, undated (Box 41)
    - "The Blind Arcade: Reflections on an Early Medieval Sarcophagus," first completed draft, undated (Box 41)
    - "The Blind Arcade: Reflections on an Early Medieval Sarcophagus," 2nd completed draft, undated (Box 41)
    - "Celestial Paradigms," draft, undated (Box 41)
    - "Vaulting the Nave," draft, 2001 July (Box 41)
    - "The Stone: Architecture as Antecedent," draft, 2001 August (Box 41)
    - 3 Drafts, undated (Box 41)
    - "Vanished Scaffolds and the Structures Thereof," drafts, 1998 November (Box 42)
    - "Incastallmento I: Perching The Village," draft, 2000 July (Box 42)
    - "Incastallmento II: Radioconcetric Villages in the Languedoc," draft, 1998 September (Box 42)
    - "Faja Oscura," draft, undated (Box 42)
    - "Psalmodi," draft, 1998 August (Box 42)
    - "The Fifth Element," draft, undated (Box 42)
    - "Mary Magdalene the Odoriferous," drafts, corrections, notes, 2000 May; 2 (Box 42)
    - Rewrites, bibliographic data, pre-publication material, 2001 April-May (Box 42)
    - "The Death of Genesis," draft, 1995; 2 (Box 42)
    - Final typescript, undated; 4 (Box 42)
  - Uncollected Historical Essays
    - "A Roman Road, The Coronation of the Virgin," draft, 2000 February; 2 (Box 43)
    - "Radiance and Obscurity: Medieval Night," draft, undated (Box 43)
    - "All the King's Mirrors," draft, 2002 September (Box 43)
    - "The Castle and the Quarries," draft, 2003 October (Box 43)
    - "Charisma and Eclipse," draft, 2003 October (Box 43)
    - "The Inaudible Aura of Bells," draft, 2003 October (Box 43)
  - In The Name of the Neither (2002)
    - "La Charlesse," draft, 1997 June (Box 43)
    - "Ode to Imminence: an Essay," "Romanesque," drafts, 1997, 1998 (Box 43)
    - "Libretto," "Towards a Grammar of Exceptions," drafts, 1997, 1998 (Box 43)
    - "Transparent Itineraries: 1997," "Stairwells: the Dissolving Steps," drafts, 1997, 1998 (Box 43)
    - "The Way of Introduction," "Madrigal," drafts, 1997, 1998 (Box 43)
    - "From a Mimosa Sketchbook," "Reliquiae," drafts, 1998 (Box 43)
    - "The Heart, Too, Goes Untitled," "Approaching the Millennium: a little Bouquet," "Languedoc," drafts, 1997, 1998 (Box 43)
    - "A Blue-Obliterative," A Self-Portrait in Late Autumn," "Of an Instrument Without Name,"A Portrait of...," drafts, 1998, 1999 (Box 43)
    - "Aphonics," "Article of Faith," "Vacant Architectures," drafts, 1999 (Box 43)
    - Final typescript, undated (Box 43)
    - Notes, fragments, rejected material, pre-publication material, undated (Box 43)
      Includes two poems and five "fugues."
  - "That Garden of Gardens"
    - Preparatory notes, 2000-2001; 2 (Box 44)
    - Early working drafts, 2001-2002; 4 (Box 44)
    - First complete draft, p. 1-36, undated (Box 44)
    - First complete draft, p. 27-84, undated (Box 44)
    - First complete draft, p. 69-125, undated (Box 44)
    - Corrected draft, 2002 (Box 44)
    - Typescript, version 1, 2002 (Box 44)
    - Photocopy of typescript, 2002 (Box 44)
    - 2nd recast, 2002 September (Box 44)
    - 2nd & 3rd recasting, 2002 November (Box 44)
    - Early drafts to rewrite, 2002-2003 (Box 45)
    - First completed drafts to rewrite, 2002 December 11 (Box 45)
    - Page 1-98, typescript to rewritten version, 2002-2003 (Box 45)
    - Page 99-126, typescript to rewritten version, 2002-2003 (Box 45)
    - 3rd recasting with corrections, 2002-2003 (Box 45)
    - Page 138-174, notes and drafts to rewrites, 2003 August (Box 45)
    - Page 148-167, Rewrites, 2003 August (Box 45)
    - Final rewrites for final version, 2003 December (Box 45)
    - Final typescript, 2003 (Box 45)
  - The Places as Preludes (2005)
    - "Prelude I-III," "Transparent Itineraries: 2000," drafts (Box 46)
    - "Prelude IV-V," "Quinces," "Testatment," drafts, undated (Box 46)
    - "Prelude VI," "In Praise of the Implicit: an Essay," "Incarnata," drafts, 2003 December (Box 46)
    - "Floralia," "The Goldbeaters," "September," drafts, 2003, 2004 (Box 46)
    - "Prelude VII-IX," "Provencal Night," drafts, 2003-2004 (Box 46)
    - "Transparent Itineraries: 2001," "Questions of Grammar 1-3," drafts (Box 46)
    - "The Physics of Verse," "Prelude X-XI," drafts, 2003-2004 (Box 46)
    - "Prelude XII-XIII," Transparent Itineraries: 2002/2003," draft (Box 46)
    - "Prelude XIV-XV," The Oval as the Object of its Own Idolatry," draft, 2002 (Box 46)
    - "Mirabandus," "Bundle: in Defense of Metaphor," "Naiad," "Mediterranean," drafts, 2004 (Box 46)
    - "Prelude XVI-XVIII," draft, 2002-2003 (Box 46)
    - "Omitted poems and Sundry fragments," "Portrait of a Lady," "Poem," "Cicadas," "The Pronouns," drafts, 1999-2003 (Box 46)
    - Final typescript, undated (Box 46)
    - Photocopy of typescript, 2004 (Box 46)
    - Photocopy of "Talisman" proofsheets, 2005 (Box 46)
    - Proofsheets with corrections, 2005 (Box 46)
    - Original draft envelopes, undated (Box 46)
  - Ambrogio Magnaghi: The Miracle Depicted (2004)
    - "Ambrogio Magnaghi: The Miracle Depicted" book published by Skira, 2004 (Box 47)
    - "The Miracle Depicted," preparatory notes, 2002 (Box 47)
    - First draft to monograph, 2002 (Box 47)
    - First completed draft, undated (Box 47)
    - First completed draft corrected and final typescript, undated (Box 47)
    - Proofsheets from Skira, 2003 (Box 47)
  - "In Light of Such Losses"
    - First Version, draft, 2003 (Box 47)
    - 2nd Version, draft, 2004 (Box 47)
    - 3rd Version, draft, 2004 March; 2 (Box 47)
    - 3rd Version, reworked, 2004 June (Box 47)
    - Draft to 4th Version, 2004 August; 2 (Box 47)
    - Page 1-105, 4th Version, rewritten draft, 2004 July-August; 2 (Box 47)
    - Page 106-154, 4th Version, draft, 2004 July-August; 2 (Box 48)
    - Page 1-90, final typescript, 2004 November (Box 48)
    - Page 91-161, final typescript, 2004 November (Box 48)
    - "Comments, Commentaries of a Literary Nature," draft, 1995-1996 (Box 48)
      "Includes: "Book Statement for Talisman," "The Poem as Path," "Three for Roland Barthes," "A Few Stray Comments on the Cultivation of the Lyric," "A Tribute to William Bronk," "For Paul Cohen," "Statement for Geoffrey O'Brien," "Statement for New World Writing"
    - Interview with Edward Foster, 1992 March (Box 48)
    - Interview with Leonard Schwartz, 2000 Summer (Box 48)
    - Writings on 2 films: "Voyage to Italy," "Last Year in Marienbad," drafts, undated (Box 48)
    - Music Hears: A Discourse, undated (Box 48)
    - Pocket Notebooks, 2000-2004; 2 (Box 48)